Albert Edelmann

Frontend Developer

Former 11 years experienced Production Engineer that changed career path to Web Development. I believe that high performance indicates a good piece of engineering, it's one of my top goals. I am target oriented, proactive, adventurous, assiduous, animated and passionate by learning new technologies.

☑ albert.edelmann@gmail.com	☐ Phone number
in /www.linkedin.com/in/albert-edelmann	3 albert.edelmann
ajedelmann.github.io/portfolio	

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

mm / 2019 - mm / 2020

DCI Digital Career Institute GmbH

City, Country

Engineer's degreeProduction Engineering

Unifass

mm / 2009 - mm / 2014 City, Country

BachareladoPublicidade, Propaganda e Marketing

Universidade Presbiteriana Mackenzie

mm / 2000 - mm / 2004 City, Country

WORK EXPERIENCE

Expediting and VQS Manager

Hatch

Feb / 2014 - Jul / 2016 Achivements / Tasks São Paulo e Região, Brasil

Lead technical negotiations with suppliers in order to mitigate quality, costs and schedule impacts; Issue and release Technical Specifications, Histogram and Working Plan; Coordinate the Expediting, VQS and Logistics team during the whole Post Award phase at project Hydro-Alunorte, see less

Engineering Consultant

Petrobras, SGS UK, E&IM and Embratecno

Aug / 2016 - Dec / 2018 Achivements / Tosks Berlin, Germany

As a Consultant Engineer, I follow-up and testify the quality tests of equipments and materials on behalf of my customers in factory shops located in Europe and Asia.

Procurement Team Lead

Consórcio UFN3

May / 2012 - Jan / 2014 Achivements / Tasks

São Paulo e Região, Brasil

Coordinated the expediting and inspection team, in order to ensure that all the hundreds of suppliers linked to this Project complied with the contract terms and reqs. Coordinated and performed KOMs at national and international vendors in order to align them with project directives and to avoid losing control of supply schedule. Performed PIM and Expediting meetings at national and international vendors (located in Brazil, Europe, North America and Asia) see less

WORK EXPERIENCE

Procurement Contract Specialist

Camargo Corrêa

Jan / 2007 - Apr / 2012

Achivements / Tasks

São Paulo e Região, Brasil

During 5 years of work on this Brazilian multinational company, I was involved in 3 major projects: 2010 to 2012 –
International Expediter Lead and Contract Management Project: RNEST (Energy Transmission line Construction) Client:
PETROBRAS Oil & Gas 2009 to 2010 – Procurement Coordinator Project: UÍGE (Energy Transmission line Construction)
Client: ANGOLA GOVERNMENT Infrastructure 2007 to 2009 – Procurement Analyst Project: ALUMAR (Alluminium Refinery
Expansion) Client: ALCOA Light Metals see less



PROJECTS

CVFY

Project description A platform that provides CV, Cover Letter templates and a text editor with many features to import data, customize them and convert them to pdf. Main used technologies: Frontend -> React, Context API, Hooks, Redux, Cloudinary, SASS and CSS Backend -> MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, Node.js, AWS and Puppeteer Support technologies -> Visual Studio, GitHub and Trello

Roman Calculator

Project description A calculator that can add, subtract and multiply Roman numerals. Built with: React Hooks - for all the UI components JavaScript - to handle calculation and validations (with Regex) CSS - No frameworks, just pure CSS Jest and React testing library - for unit tests

Jammming

Project description A website builded with React fetching data from Spotify API to allow users to search the Spotify library, create a custom playlist, then save it to their Spotify account.

React Todo app

Project description Full Stack application builded with: React (frontend) and Redux fetching data from my owm API builded with Node.js and MongoDB (backend)

React Ravenous

Project description Builded with React, Node.js and fetching data from Yelp API

LANGUAGES

English German B1 B1

Portuguese Spanish

B1 B1